<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reflective on jackbduncan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/reflective/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reflective on jackbduncan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/reflective/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Toxic Insecurity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/230316_toxicinsecurity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/230316_toxicinsecurity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Insecurity and low self-esteem have been persistent mental health challenges for me throughout my life. These issues began around the age of 9, when I started comparing myself to others more frequently. One of the more toxic consequences of these issues has been its impact in romantic relationships.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My thought pattern typically goes like this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I am not unique or special.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I am easily replaceable.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If we break up, I give my partner a chance to find someone who is unique/special/irreplaceable.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;By breaking up, I am doing them a favour and giving them the opportunity to find a better partner.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I detach from the relationship and instigate a breakup.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A song thats stuck with me on this, and has probably negatively impacted my thought process, is &amp;ldquo;Molly&amp;rdquo; by Lil Dicky. It&amp;rsquo;s about an ex-boyfriend who regrets his past decisions and inability to care for a girl, focusing on his perceived replaceability and lack of contribution to the relationship. One particular line, &amp;ldquo;You could find another me tomorrow, and that&amp;rsquo;s the hardest pill to swallow,&amp;rdquo; almost perfectly describes how I’ve felt when I’ve been in romantic relationships.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leaving Home</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/221116_leavinghome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/221116_leavinghome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Almost everyone that I know who has ever spoken to me about my dreams in life would be able to tell you that I’ve never seen my long-term future in the UK. Since I can remember, and have been able to contemplate such things, I’ve wanted to explore and live somewhere else in the world. For the most part this has been North America (mainly the United States), and while over time that specific part of the dream has waned, I’ve never properly considered staying.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
