<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on jackbduncan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on jackbduncan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Website Improvements</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Migrate posts from previous blog&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Add social media links/tags&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Add a colour scheme (thinking either Rwanda or Chelsea colours)&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Add photos section&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Figure out how to add a gallery for both photos section and 100 plots project&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Figure out how to do image resizing properly&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Add reading time + progress bar&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Make TV Shows and Movies pages more exciting - add the screen art for each of the pieces of media&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Write a little bit about some of the movies/tv shows and why you like them&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add google analytics&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Improve general appearance - look at some different fonts&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optimise photo loading for photos page&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fix icon background&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Change branding of website to focus on it being personal - move serious writing to substack as primary method of distribution&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Create a link tree or google doc that let&amp;rsquo;s people choose which one they want to engage with&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Maybe do Chelsea colours for personal website - think that would be nice&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add a filter for essays/quick writing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/writing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I want to write more and the best way to write more is to find the things that I find most compelled to write about. This is a living list of things that I find interesting and want to write about in the future.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Who I admire (cover the qualities they tend to have, feels like I have a &amp;rsquo;type&amp;rsquo; of person that I look up to)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Rwanda disability statistics (there are lots of canes/walking sticks available for purchase here which I find somewhat odd)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Air quality/how much have I potentially reduced life moving to poor air quality city&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Noise pollution - specifically around why it is a big deal and how big a deal it is, maybe approaching a general explainer&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Economics of remittances&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Scottish drug problem&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Curation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;N.B. I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that finding topics to write about is similar to buying books. It&amp;rsquo;s fun and easy to do the initial part, the sitting down and actually writing (reading) is much harder and you end up with loads of ideas just left on the shelves collecting dust. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to keep that to a minimum.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
