<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on jackbduncan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on jackbduncan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week of Blogging</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/250406_weekofblogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/250406_weekofblogging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello world. It has been a long time (over a year) since I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to follow through and write a blog post. A lot has happened in that time and as of yesterday I have finally felt somewhat on top of my life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To commemarate such a joyous event I&amp;rsquo;m going to write a blog post every day this week with the aspiration of actually getting this going with a large collection of writing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kigali Update #3 </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/240118_kigalupdatethree/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/240118_kigalupdatethree/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it’s been a hot minute since I’ve done one of these and is now actually a 3.5 update but ce la vie.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It feels like a lot and nothing has happened in the past 6 months. I’ve travelled a ridiculous amount, having been to Tanzania/Zanzibar twice, trip home + Denmark for Christmas/New Year’s, a birthday trip to Mozambique/Eswatini, and a family holiday to the Seychelles. On the work front I saw the end of a project that was both very rewarding and frustrating for various reasons. And I’ve made and lost a bunch of friends to the natural churn of expat living in Kigali.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feeling Small</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/231129_feelingsmall/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/231129_feelingsmall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m spending the week in the northern city of Musanze. It’s for work, and most of my day is spent sitting in a small conference room at a hotel with my colleagues. Living here I’ve chosen to stay in modest accommodation, costing around £8 per night. It’s still in the main city area but closer to the locals than I’m used to in Kigali.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Walking down the streets here I can’t help but feel intense guilt and sadness about the state of poverty. On my way back to the conference room from a café I saw a disabled person dragging themselves along the street. They had guards on their legs to stop them scraping and flip flops on their hands to protect from the ground. I walked past knowing that if I looked back I would be asked for money, so I didn’t. It’s the worst I’ve felt about not giving money since arriving here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Outsourcing Thinking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/231002_outsourcingthinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/231002_outsourcingthinking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been increasingly using ChatGPT as part of my role and in my personal life for various tasks. This was originally mostly limited to niche coding tasks that I needed help with, or reformatting code that I&amp;rsquo;d already done. It&amp;rsquo;s saved me a fair amount of time and lets me do more work in a day than I otherwise would have.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, over time, I&amp;rsquo;ve started using it for daily tasks that I could realistically do on my own in not much longer than it takes to prompt + edit the outputs. And I think that&amp;rsquo;s dangerous for my ability to do my job. Each time I pass the work on I&amp;rsquo;m becoming less familiar with how to do it myself and the learning that comes with doing tasks repetitively. While this is fine for mundane tasks, the more I outsource higher-level tasks, the more I outsource the actual learning and thinking that comes along with it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Consider Becoming a Civil Service Economist (UK)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/230908_civilserviceeconomist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/230908_civilserviceeconomist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Competitive starting pay in line with median salaries for economics graduates.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Strong pension schemes offering both defined benefit and defined contribution options.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ample opportunities for skill development and continuous learning through the Government Economics Service.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;High potential for social impact working on major national issues.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Excellent flexibility, allowing for a balanced work-life experience.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Opens doors for various career paths both within and outside of the civil service.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With applications for the Civil Service Fast Stream about to open I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write a bit about why you should consider becoming a civil service economist.  It&amp;rsquo;s a great career path that has competitive pay, interesting work, loads of flexibility, and can enable your future career across a range of options.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing More</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/230830_writingmore/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/230830_writingmore/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I want to write more. I want to write a lot more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I want to take more notes, I want to journal more frequently, and I want to blog more frequently too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently re-read Paul Grahams Essay &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.paulgraham.com/writing44.html&#34;&gt;Writing, Briefly&lt;/a&gt; and it affirmed what I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about recently with respect to writing. Writing, and especially writing frequently, is so important for increasing your ability to learn and grow, your ability to communicate with the world, and a whole host of other positive outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kigali Update #2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/230824_kigaliupdatetwo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/230824_kigaliupdatetwo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work:&lt;/strong&gt; Projects starting to take shape, better understanding of Rwandan work culture, feel like I&amp;rsquo;m actually effective.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Travel:&lt;/strong&gt; Want to do write-ups for the places I&amp;rsquo;ve been, visit home was enjoyable but busy, excited for upcoming trips.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Sports/Social:&lt;/strong&gt; Getting into a better routine fitness wise, have made some good friends, board games nights becoming a success.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Misc.:&lt;/strong&gt; Car has been a nightmare and waste of money, better health after dietary changes.             &lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Overall:&lt;/strong&gt; Feeling content, excited for what&amp;rsquo;s ahead.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goals [July - December 2023]</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/230722_julydecembergoals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/230722_julydecembergoals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This past week I’ve been feeling a bit lost about what to do. Work isn&amp;rsquo;t taking enough of my time or mental energy to keep me stimulated, and I’ve not found any side projects that pique my interest. I think part of this has to do with not having any concrete goals right now – I have some longer-term ones in the back of my head, like where I want to go after this job and a broader scope of how I want the next 5 years to go, but nothing for the next 6 months – 1 year. So, I thought I would write some down.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kigali Update #1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/230409_kigaliupdateone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/230409_kigaliupdateone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s coming up on the 4-month anniversary of me moving to Kigali (1/6th of the time I’ll be here) so I thought I’d write down some thoughts and reflections of my experience so far.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conceptually it’s been a bit odd thinking about how different my life/world is now compared to a year ago. I hadn’t even been properly considering leaving home for another year or two and it wasn’t going to be for a low-income country. I was applying to the program that brought me here on a whim following a recommendation from my manager at the time, and in my head wasn’t really considering it as a genuine opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI and Language</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/230403_ailanguage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/230403_ailanguage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the largest and most immediate impacts of GPT-4 and other emerging AI technology, like Whisper, Midjourney, and text-to-speech generation, is going to be on language.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are three key areas where I think it’ll be applied in the near future, which are learning languages, media translation, and creation of a real life babel fish.  I finish up with some thoughts on what it might mean for work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning Language&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toxic Insecurity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/230316_toxicinsecurity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/230316_toxicinsecurity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Insecurity and low self-esteem have been persistent mental health challenges for me throughout my life. These issues began around the age of 9, when I started comparing myself to others more frequently. One of the more toxic consequences of these issues has been its impact in romantic relationships.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My thought pattern typically goes like this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I am not unique or special.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I am easily replaceable.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If we break up, I give my partner a chance to find someone who is unique/special/irreplaceable.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;By breaking up, I am doing them a favour and giving them the opportunity to find a better partner.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I detach from the relationship and instigate a breakup.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A song thats stuck with me on this, and has probably negatively impacted my thought process, is &amp;ldquo;Molly&amp;rdquo; by Lil Dicky. It&amp;rsquo;s about an ex-boyfriend who regrets his past decisions and inability to care for a girl, focusing on his perceived replaceability and lack of contribution to the relationship. One particular line, &amp;ldquo;You could find another me tomorrow, and that&amp;rsquo;s the hardest pill to swallow,&amp;rdquo; almost perfectly describes how I’ve felt when I’ve been in romantic relationships.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leaving Home</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/221116_leavinghome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/221116_leavinghome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Almost everyone that I know who has ever spoken to me about my dreams in life would be able to tell you that I’ve never seen my long-term future in the UK. Since I can remember, and have been able to contemplate such things, I’ve wanted to explore and live somewhere else in the world. For the most part this has been North America (mainly the United States), and while over time that specific part of the dream has waned, I’ve never properly considered staying.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog Posts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recommendations/blogposts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recommendations/blogposts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://worksinprogress.co/issue/the-housing-theory-of-everything&#34;&gt;The Housing Theory of Everything&lt;/a&gt; by Sam Bowman, John Myers and Ben Southwood&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2018/10/high-return-activity-raising-others-aspirations.html&#34;&gt;The high-return activity of raising others’ aspirations&lt;/a&gt; by Tyler Cowen&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.slowboring.com/p/energy-abundance&#34;&gt;The case for more energy&lt;/a&gt; by Matthew Yglesias&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elidourado.com/p/cargo-airships&#34;&gt;Cargo airships could be big&lt;/a&gt; by Eli Dourado&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elidourado.com/p/50-years-supersonic-ban&#34;&gt;50 years of silence&lt;/a&gt; by Eli Dourado&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tomforth.co.uk/northernlands/&#34;&gt;North England vs. The Netherlands&lt;/a&gt; by Tom Forth&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.paulgraham.com/writing44.html&#34;&gt;Writing, Briefly&lt;/a&gt; by Paul Graham&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Books</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recommendations/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recommendations/books/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a list of books that I would recommend. My goodreads profile is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/user/show/146508944-jack-d&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; where I have more detailed ratings/reviews.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;economic-development&#34;&gt;Economic Development&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Next Factory of the World by Irene Yuan Sun&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How Asia Works by Joe Studwell&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;economic-policy&#34;&gt;Economic Policy&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open Borders by Bryan Kaplan&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Triumph of the City by Edward Glaeser&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The New Geography of Jobs by Enrico Morreti&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Narconomics by Tom Wainwright&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Billion Americans by Matthew Ygelsias&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Movies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recommendations/movies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recommendations/movies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kung Fu Panda (2008)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Moana (2016)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Everything Everwhere All At Once (2022)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Good Will Hunting (1997)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Spotlight (2015)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My Cousin Vinny (1992)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How To Lose a Guy in 10 Days (2003)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quotes and Tweets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recommendations/quotestweets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recommendations/quotestweets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Be the change you want to see in the world&amp;rdquo; - Mahatma Ghandi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am, somehow, less interested in the weight and convolutions of Einstein&amp;rsquo;s brain than in the near certainty that people of equal talent have lived and died in cotton fields and sweatshops.&amp;rdquo; - Stephen Jay Gould&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If I have seen further it is by standing on the shoulders of Giants” - Isaac Newton&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Ever tried. Ever failed. No matter. Try again. Fail again. Fail better.” - Samuel Beckett&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TV Shows</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recommendations/tv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recommendations/tv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Scrubs (S1 - S8)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The West Wing (S1 - S4)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Thick of It&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Peep Show&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Desperate Housewives&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Avatar the Last Airbender&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Full Metal Alchemist: Brotherhood&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Website Improvements</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Migrate posts from previous blog&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Add social media links/tags&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Add a colour scheme (thinking either Rwanda or Chelsea colours)&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Add photos section&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Figure out how to add a gallery for both photos section and 100 plots project&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Figure out how to do image resizing properly&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Add reading time + progress bar&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Make TV Shows and Movies pages more exciting - add the screen art for each of the pieces of media&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Write a little bit about some of the movies/tv shows and why you like them&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add google analytics&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Improve general appearance - look at some different fonts&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optimise photo loading for photos page&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fix icon background&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Change branding of website to focus on it being personal - move serious writing to substack as primary method of distribution&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Create a link tree or google doc that let&amp;rsquo;s people choose which one they want to engage with&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Maybe do Chelsea colours for personal website - think that would be nice&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add a filter for essays/quick writing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/writing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I want to write more and the best way to write more is to find the things that I find most compelled to write about. This is a living list of things that I find interesting and want to write about in the future.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Who I admire (cover the qualities they tend to have, feels like I have a &amp;rsquo;type&amp;rsquo; of person that I look up to)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Rwanda disability statistics (there are lots of canes/walking sticks available for purchase here which I find somewhat odd)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Air quality/how much have I potentially reduced life moving to poor air quality city&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Noise pollution - specifically around why it is a big deal and how big a deal it is, maybe approaching a general explainer&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Economics of remittances&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Scottish drug problem&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Curation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;N.B. I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that finding topics to write about is similar to buying books. It&amp;rsquo;s fun and easy to do the initial part, the sitting down and actually writing (reading) is much harder and you end up with loads of ideas just left on the shelves collecting dust. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to keep that to a minimum.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
